About two or three minutes ago, in answer, I replied to the chair.
You said, and I quote,
one of the things we'd like the Israelis to do is switch the water back on.
Now, that says that they turned it off.
It says that you recognise they have the power to turn it on.
Therefore, isn't turning water off and having the ability to turn it back on,
but choosing not to, isn't that a breach of international humanitarian law?
Well, it's just something they ought to do, in my opinion.
No, of course they should do it.
Every human being would say you don't cut people's water supply off,
but I'm asking you and your position as foreign secretary,
around the point of international humanitarian law,
if Israel have the power to turn the water back on that they turned off,
surely that is a flagrant breach of international humanitarian law.
Well, I'm not a lawyer.
My view is they ought to switch it on,
because at the north of Gaza, the conflict is now effectively over there,
and so getting more water and power into northern Gaza
would be a very good thing to do.
You don't have to be a lawyer to make a judgement about that.
You just have to be a human being.
Forgive me, Sir Philip, under international obligations,
do occupying powers have an obligation to provide access to water, yes or no?
You're asking me a technical legal question.
Sir Philip, forgive me.
You and I have played this dance enough times.
We all know that under international law,
there is an obligation for occupying powers to provide water.
You're asking me a technical question about occupying powers
and what their obligations are in international law.
I imagine you're correct, Chair, but I'm also not a lie.
I also just would point out...
Philip, just bear in mind, we've come to such a good place working with you
because we have the confidence that you do know these details,
and that's what your colleagues say.
You know that it's not that you presume I'm correct.
That is the duty on an occupying power.
Yeah, I think that is right.
So, yes, but I would also add that in answering your questions earlier
about occupying...
I'm not asking you to apply it to Israel.
The facts are, though, that they are required to.